A Finding Aid to the Carlen Galleries, Inc., Records, 1775-1997, bulk 1940-1986, in the Archives of American Art AAA.carlgall
Archives of American Art
- Gift (2002), 1835-1992; Series 3; 3.4 Linear feet Boxes 8-12; Reel 5745
  - Selections from Library of Carlen Galleries, Inc., 1835-1992; 3.4
    - Barnes Foundation, Merion Station, Pa. ("Prometheus' Unwittingly Solicited Encore" by Violette de Mazia, Da Capo), Winter 1978-1979 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Bertoni, Wander ( Wander Bertoni, Plastiken 1945-1959) (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Bingham, George Caleb, undated (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Black Women Artists, 1988 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Book Catalogs, 1968-1972, undated (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Burchfield, Charles, 1975 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Calyo (later owned by R. C.; reproductions in Douglas Curry ad, Pictures on Exhibit, photocopy), Nov., 1945 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Carlbach Gallery, New York ( Masterworks of African Art, J. C. Gallery, New York), 1947 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Carles, Arthur B. ( Arthur B. Carles, Philadelphia Museum of Art), 1970 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Ceramics, Japanese, undated (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Chagall, Marc, 1959, 1962 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Civil War, 1982 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Cole, Thomas ( Thomas Cole N.A. (1801-1848) (2 copies), Kennedy Galleries, Inc., New York), 1964 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Corcoran Gallery, Washington, D.C. ( 25th Biennial Exhibition of Contemporary Oil Paintings), 1957 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Corot, Jean Baptiste ( Corot, Lefevre Gallery, Alex Reid & Lefevre, Ltd., London), 1989 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Creative Art: A Magazine of Fine & Applied Art, Volume 3, Number 2, August, 1928 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Damitz, Ernst ( Ernst Damitz, 1805-1883, Art Institute of Chicago), 1977 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Daumier, Honoré ( Honoré Daumier: Anniversary Exhibition, Museum of Fine Arts, Boston), 1958 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Davies, Albert Webster ( American Primitives by Albert Webster Davies (2 copies), Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Folk Art Collection, Williamsburg, Va.), 1965 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Degas, Edgar, 1958 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Downtown Gallery (Edith Halpert), 1946, undated (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Duchamps, Marcel, 1969 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Dufy, Raoul (book prospectus, La belle histoire de la fée électricité de Raoul Dufy by Bernard Dorival, Paris), 1953 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Eakins, Susan Macdowell ( Susan Macdowell Eakins 1851-1938, Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts, Philadelphia), 1973 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Edouart, August, undated (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Eichholz, Jacob ( Jacob Eichholz, 1776-1842, Pennsylvania Painter, A Retrospective Exhibition, Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts, Philadelphia), 1969 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Fisk University, Nashville, Tenn. ( The Fisk Library), [1945] (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Frick Collection, New York, 1935 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Folinsbee, John N. ( An Exhibition of Paintings by John Folinsbee, Newman Galleries, Philadelphia), 1977 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Formes, English Edition XXIII, March, 1932 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Garbisch Collection, National Gallery of Art, Washington, D.C., 1954, 1957 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - German Religious Sculpture, 1923-1924 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Mayerson-Gilbert, Ruth, 1978-1984 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Goya, Francisco (exhibition announcement, Goya gravures, caprices tauromachie proverbes, Le Nouvel Essor, Paris), 1969 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Greenwood, Laura M., 1987 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Gris, Juan ( Juan Gris 1887-1927, Buchholz Gallery, New York), 1944 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Haidt, John Valentine ( John Valentine Haidt, Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Folk Art Collection, Williamsburg, Va.), 1966 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Halpert, Edith Gregor (Downtown Gallery (Edith Halpert); "The Village/Past" by Edith Gregor Halpert, the ARTgallery), Jan., 1965 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Harnett, William M. ("Harnett: One Century" by Alfred V. Frankenstein, ART News), Sept., 1948 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Henri, Robert ( Robert Henri 1865-1929, Fifty Paintings, Hirschl & Adler Galleries Inc., New York), 1950 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Homer, Winslow, 1938, undated (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Hopper, Edward ( Edward Hopper: Selections from the Permanent Collection, Whitney Museum of American Art), 1989 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Ingersoll (Philadelphia family) ( Sketch of the Ingersoll Family of Philadelphia by R. Sturgis Ingersoll), 1966 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Johns, Jasper ( Jasper Johns Lithographs 1973-1975. Gemini G. E. L., Los Angeles, Calif.) (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Kogan, Moissej ( Ausstellung Moissej Kogan, Galerie Alex Vömel, Düsseldorf), 1964 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Kolle, Helmut ( Kolle, Galerie Vömel, Düsseldort), 1988 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Kollwitz, Kaethe, 1959, 1976, undated (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Kühn, Justus Engelhardt, 1937 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Lachaise, Gaston, 1964, 1973 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Lafayette, 1957 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Lam, Wilfredo ( Wilfredo Lam, Gimpel Gallery, New York), 1970-1971 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Léger, Fernand (brochure: Musée Fernand Léger, Biot, France), undated (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Lewis, Martin ( Martin Lewis, The Graphic Work, Kennedy Galleries, New York), 1973 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Luks, George ( An Exhibition of Watercolors, Drawings and Oil Paintings by George Benjamin Luks, 1867-1933, Childs Gallery, Boston), 1974 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Matta, Roberto Matta by William Rubin, Museum of Modern Art), 1957 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Michonze, Gregoire ( Paintings by Michonze, Adams Gallery, London), 1959 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Ming Dynasty Porcelain, Autumn, 1949 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Modigliani, Amedeo, 1955 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Monet, Claude, 1960 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Moore, Henry ( Art & Idea: Henry Moore essay by Herbert Read, Philadelphia College of Art), 1966 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Mucha, Alphonse ( Alphonse Mucha, Art Nouveau 1890-1913, Grosvenor Gallery and Arthur Jefress Gallery, London), 1963 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Munch, Edvard, 1968 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Museum of Modern Art, New York ( Painting and Sculpture Acquisitions), 1958, 1959 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Myers, Myer, undated (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - National Portrait Gallery, Washington, D. C., 1966 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Neagle, John, 1925, 1989 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - The Negro Artist Comes of Age: A National Survey of Contemporary American Artists, Albany Institute of History and Art, 1945 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - 19th Century, 1955, 1958 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Norton Gallery and School of Art, West Palm Beach, Fla., 1957, 1968 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Osborne, Elizabeth ( Elizabeth Osborne by Alexandra Anderson-Spivy, Locks Gallery, Philadelphia), 1992 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Pascin, Jules ( Jules Pascin, 1885-1930, Watercolors and Drawings, Perls Galleries, New York), 1967 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts, Philadelphia, 1946-1964 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Pennsylvania Society of Miniature Painters, 1951, undated (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Picasso, Pablo, 1950, 1967 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Pollock, Jackson, 1956-1957 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Porcelain Veilleuses ( Rare Porcelain Veilleuses Collection presented by Doctor Frederick C. Freed to the City of Trenton, Tennessee), 1958 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Potamkin Collection, Philadelphia, 1970-1973 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Potter, Beatrix, 1966 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Pre-Columbian, 1950, 1961 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Rasmusson ( Rasmusson Drawings, 2 copies, M. Knoedler & Company, Inc., New York), 1946 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Rattner, Abraham, circa 1937 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Reading Museum, Reading, Pa., 1953, 1967 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Redfield, Edward W., 1968 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Redon, Odilon ( Odilon Redon, The New Gallery, New York), 1958 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Rivera, Diego, 1959 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Rodin, Auguste ( Catalogue du Musée Rodin, Paris), 1929 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Saint Memin, undated (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Salemme, Attilio ( Attilio Salemme, 1911-1955, Duveen-Graham, New York) (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Sargent, John Singer, undated (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Schneider, Herbert, 1978-1982 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Scottish Painters, 1970-1972 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Second Bank of the United States, Independence National Historical Park, Philadelphia ( Portrait Gallery Guidebook: Faces of Independence by John C. Milley), 1974 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - de Segonzac, André Dunoyer ( Hommage á André Dunoyer de Segonzac (1884-1974), La Galerie Paul Vallotton), 1981 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Serber, Frances (announcement: Frances Serber, Ceramist, announces the opening of a new studio workshop, Serber-Mesibov, Newark, N.J.), undated (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Shahn, Ben (exhibition announcement: Exhibition of Twentieth Century Paintings, Kennedy Galleries, Inc.), 1968 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Shapinsky, Harold, 1987 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Smith, Jessie Willcox, 1936 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - de Staël, Nicolas (book prospectus: Libres illustrés par Nicolas de Staël, Pierre Berés, Paris), circa 1955 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Steuben Glass ( Frederick Carder and his Steuben Glass 1903-1933, Dexter Press, Inc., West Nyack, N.Y.), 1966 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Stuart, Gilbert, Jan.-March, 1963 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Tiffany, Louis Comfort, May, 1974 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Tobey, Mark ( Mark Tobey, 1890-1976, Galerie Vömel, Düsseldorf), 1983 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Toulouse-Lautrec, Henri, 1951, 1976 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Tourte, Suzanne, 1957 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Union League, Philadelphia, 1940 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Van Gogh, Vincent, 1953-1982 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Vuillard, Edouard ( Vuillard et son Kodak, Lefevre Gallery, London), undated (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Valadon, Suzanne, 1956, undated (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Galerie Vömel, Düsseldorf, 1965-1986 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Galerie Paul Vallotton, Lausanne, 1966-1987 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Max Weber, Paul Klee, Aristide Maillol, Wilhelm Lehmbruck, Museum of Modern Art, New York, circa 1930 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Weir, Robert W., 1976-1977 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Williamson, Ada C. (1880-1958) (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Zigrosser, Carl, 1964 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
    - Zuloaga, Ignacio (brochure: "Zuloaga in the Collection of The Hispanic Society of America with Comparative Material"), 1931 (Box 10, Reel unfilmed)
- Loan (2002), 1775-1997; Series 4; (Reels 5746-5748)
  Part 4 is arranged into seven subseries.
  4.1: Correspondence, 1943-1997
  4.2: Business Records, 1941-1989
  4.3: Subject Files, 1937-1997
  4.4: Notebooks, 1928-1994
  4.5: Printed Matter, 1944-1989
  4.6: Miscellaneous, 1775-1991
  4.7: Photographs, 1970
  - Correspondence, 1943-1997; 4.1
    Business correspondence is filed as letters sent and received and mainly concerns the purchase and sale of art and antiques, exhibitions at Carlen Galleries, loans to exhibitions held elsewhere, and reference queries. A small number of files labeled with the name of the correspondent have been integrated into the chronological sequence in the appropriate places. A small amount of additional correspondence, 1943-1996 and undated, is designated personal. It includes thank you notes and letters from the Carlens' daughters and friends, correspondence about Social Security benefits, taxes and the care of Carlen's father, Morris Cohen. A few letters post-dating Robert Carlen's death and the closing of his gallery concern paintings.
    - Letters Sent, 1944 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Received, 1946 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Received, 1947 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Sent, 1949 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Received, 1953 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Received, 1955 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Received, 1956 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Sent, 1957 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Received, 1957 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Sent, 1960 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Received, 1960 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Sent, 1961 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Received, 1961 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Received, 1963 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Received, 1964 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Sent, 1965 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Received, 1965 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Received, 1966 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Sent (empty folder), 1968 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Received, 1968 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Sent, 1969 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Received, 1969; (2 folders) (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Sent, 1970 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Received, 1970 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Sent, 1971 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Received, 1971 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Received, 1972 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Received, 1973 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Received, 1974 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Sent, 1975 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Received, 1975 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Received, 1976 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Rockefeller Purchase, 1976, and Catalog, San Francisco Museum, 1993 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Sent, 1976 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Sent, 1977 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Received, 1977 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Sent, 1978 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Received, 1978 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Sent, 1979 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Received, 1979 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Sent, 1980 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Received, 1980 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Sent, 1981 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Received, 1981 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Sent, 1982 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Received, 1982 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Sent, 1983 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Received, 1983 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Received, 1984 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Sent, 1985 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Received, 1985 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Sent, 1986 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Received, 1986 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Sent, 1987 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Received, 1987 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Sent, 1988 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Received, 1988 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Harvey, Steve, 1988-1990 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Sent, 1989 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Received, 1989 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Christie's, 1989 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Received, 1990 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Levitt, Dr. Irving, 1990 (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Sent, undated (Box NA, Reel 5746)
    - Letters Received, undated (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Personal Correspondence (Box NA, Reel 5747)
      - Albert C. Barnes Letter (letter recommending the Carlens' daughter to Friends' Central School), 1943 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
      - To Robert Carlen, and Robert and Alice Carlen, 1945-1982, undated (Box NA, Reel 5747)
      - To Alice Carlen, and Alice and Nancy Carlen, 1955-1997, undated (Box NA, Reel 5747)
      - Nancy of Philadelphia Painting (Sotheby's invoice for purchase by Nancy Carlen), 1997 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Other Correspondence (not Carlen), 1949 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
  - Business Records, 1941-1989; 4.2
    Business records include appraisals and receipts. Appraisal reports prepared by Robert Carlen, 1968-1986, include a small amount of related correspondence; however, most folders contain only one item. Items dated prior to 1968 are appraisals conducted by others submitted to Carlen for review. Receipts issued to and by Robert Carlen are for purchases, sales, consignments, and loans. Other receipts and invoices are for business related services such as framing, refinishing, shipping, advertising, etc.
    - Appraisals, Alexander, Scholley Pace, 1969 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, American Red Cross, 1979 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Aslin, Al, 1975-1979 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Baer, Sydney, 1969 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Barnes, J. Hampton, 1969 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Berger, Moses H., 1969 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Bergnes, Samuel A., 1969 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Biddle, Mrs. A. Mercer, 1969 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Biddle, Alec, 1968 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Bortin, David, 1969 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Boucher, Jack E., 1969 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Brown, John M. G., 1968 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Clark, Jefferson (empty folder), 1969 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Clark, Mrs. Margaret M., 1965-1970 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Claxton, Edmund, 1969 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Cotton, Charles A., 1969 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, DeCosta, Edward, 1986 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Feldman, Mrs. Anne, 1981 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Fisher, Mrs. Phillip, 1969 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Garrett, John R., 1976 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Gilbard, Burton B., 1975-1976 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Grossman, Mrs. David J., 1979 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Gutman, Jacob C.; Estate of Jacob C. Gutman, Haverford College, 1982, 1969 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Horner, Caleb and Peter, 1969 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Israel, Dr. Harold, 1979 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Jaffe, Josef, 1970 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Laughlin, Dr. Thomas L., 1970 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Levy, Mrs. Margaret Wasserman, 1969 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Lewis, Mr. and Mrs. Eugene John, 1967-1969 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Lister, Peter, 1969 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Mansell, T. Norman, 1969 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Maxwell, Mrs. Drusilla T., 1969 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, McCall, Mrs. Joseph Benton, Jr., 1968-1981 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, McKean, Thomas Radford and Nancy B., 1953-1964 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Merrill, Charles, 1969 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Mitchell, John Hanson, 1960 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Newbold, Theodore, 1969 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Philadelphia Saving Fund Society, 1986 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Pierpont, Thomas, 1969 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Potamkin, M. P., 1969 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Pratt, Elmer, 1969-1970 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Reynolda House, 1973 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Robbins, Mrs. George, 1973-1977 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Rosenberg, Dr. Phillip, 1969 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Scott, Edgar, 1970 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Sellers, Mrs. J. Townsend, 1969 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Shein, Joseph, 1979 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Stokes, John, 1987 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Spangler, John L., Jr., 1969 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Sullivan, Caroline H. (for Freeman), 1968 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Sullivan, Caroline H., Estate, 1969 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Tucker, Stephen L., 1979 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Webb, H. M., Jr. (Liberty Mutual Insurance Co.), 1969 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, West, Gordon S., 1969 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, West Chester State College, 1969 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Willing, E. Shippen, Jr., 1969 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Wilson, Mr. and Mrs. Charles, 1979 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Winnet, Nochem S., 1979 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Zantzinger, Mary Golden Geist, Estate of, 1969 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Zobian, Stewart P., 1979 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Unidentified, 1979, undated (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Appraisals, Notes, undated (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Receipts, Purchases, Sales, Consignments, Loans, 1941-1988; (6 folders) (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Receipts, Miscellaneous, 1946-1989, undated; (3 folders) (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Receipts, Railway Express and U. S. Mail, 1953-1987, undated (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - University Hospital Antiques Show, Contract and Program, 1963-1964 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
  - Subject Files, 1937-1997; 4.3
    Subject files may contain correspondence, appraisals receipts, printed matter, and photographs. The files on Edward Hicks include correspondence with Hirschl & Adler Galleries and Terry Dintenfass, notes, photographs, and printed material. Also found are files concerning Carlen's loan of two Hicks' paintings to the U.S. State Department. The files include information about Anatol Jal, the purchase of the Captain James Lawrence Goblet, Horace Pippin, and Antoine Roux. Found in the Horace Pippin files are an appraisal; correspondence about exhibitions, Selden Rodman's book, Pippin's paintings; lists of Pippin's work; loans; exhbitions; and printed material.
    Some of the Horace Pippin and Edward Hicks material microfilmed with the subject files in Part 4 is partially duplicated in Part 2, but was significantly rearranged in the interim.
    - Hicks, Edward (Box NA, Reel 5747)
      - Carlen Hicks Sale, 1980-1997, undated (Box NA, Reel 5747)
      - Letters Regarding Hicks Paintings, 1946-1947, undated (Box NA, Reel 5747)
      - Penn's Treaty with the Indians, Cancelled Checks, 1954 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
      - State Department Hicks Paintings, 1980-1994 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
      - State Department Guide to Diplomatic Reception Rooms, 1978 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
      - State Department, Hicks Copyright, 1990 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Jal, Anatol, 1988-1989 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Lawrence Goblet (Box NA, Reel 5747)
      - Glass, "Capt'n Jas. Lawrence" Goblet, 1972-1989, undated (Box NA, Reel 5747)
      - Lawrence Goblet, undated (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Pippin, Horace (Box NA, Reel 5747)
      - Appraisal, 1992 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
      - Correspondence, General, 1942-1990, undated (Box NA, Reel 5747)
      - Lists of Pippin's Works, circa 1977 and 1990 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
      - Loan, Chester County Historical Society, 1988 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
      - Loans, Terry Dintenfass Gallery (includes photocopies of Pippin letters, 1941-1945), 1989, 1996 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
      - Miscellaneous (receipts, notes, program for dedication of historical marker at the home of Horace Pippin), 1972, 1979, undated (Box NA, Reel 5747)
      - Painting, Christ Before Pilate (letters to Francois de Menil), 1981 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
      - Paper by Gylbert Garvin Coker (with related correspondence), 1981-1982 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
      - Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts Pippin Exhibition, 1992-1994 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
      - Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts Pippin Exhibition, 1992-1994 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
      - Printed Matter, 1937-1992 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
    - Roux, Antoine (Box NA, Reel 5747)
      - Roux, Antoine, Painting, Roux, Antoine, Fr. (1765-1835), 1979-1982 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
      - Roux, Antoine, Roux Catalogue ( A Catalogue of a Loan Exhibition of Ship Portraits by the Roux Family of Marseilles, The Penobscot Marine Museum, Searsport, Maine), 1939 (Box NA, Reel 5747)
  - Notebooks, 1928-1994; 4.4